import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2008 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The non-metal among the following elements is....................",
A: "argon.",
B: "Manganese",
C: "mercury.",
D: "sodium.",
answer: "A. argon",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. Which of the following processes brings about the disintegration of a rock?",
A: "Dissociation",
B: "Metamorphosis",
C: "Moulting",
D: "Weathering",
answer: "D. Weathering",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. The organelle responsible for respiration is .......................",
A: "endoplasmic recticulum.",
B: "mitochondrion.",
C: "plasma membrane",
D: "ribosome.",
answer: "B. mitochondrion",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. An alloy containing copper and zinc as its constituent element is...........................",
A: "brass.",
B: "bronze.",
C: "duralumin.",
D: "steel.",
answer: "A. brass",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Indigestion is caused by.............................",
A: "drinking a lot of water.",
B: "taking unbalanced diet.",
C: "improper chewing of food",
D: "inadequate intake of food.",
answer: "C. improper chewing of food",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. The best way to get the cursor of the mouse to the next line when using the computer is to press the ........................",
A: "enter key.",
B: "escape key.",
C: "shift key",
D: "tab key.",
answer: "A. enter key",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. An example of a biological polymer is......................",
A: "cellulose.",
B: "dacron.",
C: "nylon.",
D: "polyethylene.",
answer: "A. cellulose",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Lime is added to soil mainly to..........................",
A: "increase water permeability.",
B: "destroy micro-organisms",
C: "remove ca11bonates.",
D: "reduce acidity.",
answer: "D. reduce acidity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. The heart is divided into left and right halves by the.......................",
A: "cardiac muscles",
B: "papillary muscles.",
C: "septum.",
D: "tendon.",
answer: "C. septum",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the following characteristics determines the colour of light?",
A: "Amplitude",
B: "Frequency",
C: "Intensity",
D: "Velocity",
answer: "B. Frequency",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. An aqueous solution of an acid............................",
A: "liberates hydrogen with active metals.",
B: "turns red litmus blue",
C: "has a soapy feel.",
D: "has a bitter taste",
answer: "A. liberates hydrogen with active metals",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. Sexual reproduction has more advantages compared with asexual reproduction mainly because it",
A: "is quicker than asexual reproduction",
B: "provides more offspring than asexual reproduction",
C: "brings about variation",
D: "takes place at all times.",
answer: "C. brings about variation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Calculate the kinetic energy of an athlete of mass 60 kg running at 8 ms-1",
A: "2.40 X 102J",
B: "2.60 X 102J",
C: "1.92 X 103J",
D: "3.84 X 103J",
answer: "C. 1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. What is the value of x in the equation: CaCO3(s) + xHCl(aq) CaCl2(s) + C02(g) + H2O(l)?",
A: "1",
B: "2",
C: "3",
D: "4",
answer: "B. 2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Exhaled air may readily put off a burning candle because it contains high levels of .......................",
A: "carbon dioxide and moisture",
B: "heat and oxygen.",
C: "nitrogen and heat",
D: "oxygen and nitrogen.",
answer: "A. carbon dioxide and moisture",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. Which of the following crosses is a, test-cress?",
A: "WW x WW",
B: "WW x Ww",
C: "Ww x ww",
D: "Ww x Ww",
answer: "C. Ww x ww",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Safety devices to be used in a chemistry laboratory include........................ \nI. A pair of goggles \nII. Nose guard \nIII. Crash helmet \nIV. Hand gloves",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "I, II and IV only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, IT, III and IV",
answer: "B. I, II and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. All the following preparations are required by a poultry farmer before his chicks arrive except",
A: "putting litter in the brooder house",
B: "putting feed in the feeders three days before chicks arrive.",
C: "washing the brooder house.",
D: "cleaning and drying the equipment in the brooder house.",
answer: "B. putting feed in the feeders three days before chicks arrive",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. Which of the following parts of a computer is an output device?",
A: "Joystick",
B: "Keyboard",
C: "Plotter",
D: "Scanner",
answer: "C. Plotter",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. Organisms with their nuclear material diffused in the cytoplasm belong to the kingdom...............",
A: "Animalia.",
B: "Fungi.",
C: "Prokaryotae.",
D: "Protoctista.",
answer: "C. Prokaryotae",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. The struggle for survival among individuals of the same species arises because ....................",
A: "they exhibit cannibalism.",
B: "they share the same limited resources together",
C: "each individual produces a large number of offspring.",
D: "each individual has an equal chance of survival.",
answer: "B. they share the same limited resources together",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. Which of the following compounds does not show covalent characteristics?",
A: "Ammonia gas",
B: "Ethanol",
C: "Hydrogen chloride",
D: "Sodium chloride",
answer: "D. Sodium chloride",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. Which of the following statements is not true about boiling and evaporation?",
A: "Boiling takes place throughout the liquid",
B: "Evaporation takes place at the surface of the liquid.",
C: "Both boiling and evaporation take place at specific temperatures",
D: "Evaporation results in cooling",
answer: "C. Both boiling and evaporation take place at specific temperatures",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The tissue which is likely to stain red when a herbaceous plant is placed in a red solution for about two hours is the .....................",
A: "cambium",
B: "Parenchyma",
C: "Phloem",
D: "xylem",
answer: "D. xylem",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Lateral inversion is a phenomenon in the reflection of light where ...................",
A: "an image is turned upside down in a plane mirror.",
B: "an image is formed outside a plane mirror.",
C: "the left hand of an object becomes the right hand of its image in a plane mirror.",
D: "an image can be projected onto a screen using a converging lens.",
answer: "C. the left hand of an object becomes the right hand of its image in a plane mirror",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The organization that delivers humanitarian assistance to victims of war is the....................",
A: "Food and Agriculture Organization.",
B: "Red Cross",
C: "United Nations Children's Fund",
D: "World Health Organization.",
answer: "B. Red Cross",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. A fruit that has a fibrous mesocarp with air spaces is likely to be dispersed by ......................",
A: "animals.",
B: "explosive mechanism",
C: "water.",
D: "wind.",
answer: "C. water",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Which of the following statement is not correct about X-rays?",
A: "They cause fluorescence",
B: "They are deflected by electric fields",
C: "They can produce ionization",
D: "They can be diffracted.",
answer: "B. They are deflected by electric fields",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Fish can be stored longest when..........................",
A: "salted wet.",
B: "salted and dried.",
C: "smoked.",
D: "frozen.",
answer: "B. salted and dried",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Ornamental plants are grown for all the following reasons except ........................",
A: "beautification.",
B: "pasture.",
C: "pleasure.",
D: "shade.",
answer: "B. pasture",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Which of the following factors influences the availability of some nutrients in the soil?",
A: "Soil depth",
B: "Soil colour",
C: "Soil consistency",
D: "Soil pH",
answer: "A. Soil depth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Asbestos suits are used by fire: fighters because they are.......................... \nI. heat-resistant. \nII. non-combustible. \nIII. poor conductors",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. A poultry stockman tests his eggs at the beginning of the incubation period in order to..............",
A: "eliminate infertile eggs                                     . B. know the stage of development of the embryo",
C: "eliminate eggs that are underweight",
D: "eliminate eggs that will not hatch in time.",
answer: "C. eliminate eggs that are underweight",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. In Ghana, laws and regulations which prohibit abuse of the environment include...................",
A: "legislation on land tenure",
B: "legislation on soil conservation.",
C: "convention on the ozone layer.",
D: "laws on bush fires",
answer: "D. laws on bush fires",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Ventilation is essential in the construction of houses because it........................",
A: "creates conditions that favour the growth of fungi.",
B: "allows cool air to circulate in the room.",
C: "replaces humid stagnant air with dry air",
D: "allows bad odour in the room to escape.",
answer: "B. allows cool air to circulate in the room",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The addition of lime [Ca(OH)2] in the water treatment process is to ...........................",
A: "kill bacteria and other micro-organisms",
B: "aid sedimentation of suspended particles.",
C: "adjust the pH of the water and partially remove hardness",
D: "ensure effective filtration of raw water.",
answer: "C. adjust the pH of the water and partially remove hardness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following ingredients are sources of protein for poultry?",
A: "Soyabean cake and cassava meal",
B: "Blood meal and soyabean cake",
C: "Cassava meal and blood meal",
D: "Wheat bran and fish meal",
answer: "B. Blood meal and soyabean cake",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The importance of a fuse in an electric circuit is to ...................",
A: "provide protection against electric shock",
B: "protect electrical appliances from being damaged.",
C: "control electrical leakage",
D: "protect the house from thunder and lightning.",
answer: "B. protect electrical appliances from being damaged",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. A brooder covering 15 m2 can accommodate 100 chicks. How many chicks can be kept comfortably in a brooder of area 3000m2?",
A: "300",
B: "450",
C: "20,000",
D: "31,500",
answer: "C. 20,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. Which of the following process make use of the beneficial effects of microbes? \nI. Baking of bread \nII. Manufacture of antibiotics \nIII. Brewing of beer",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Determine the relative molecular mass of Ca(OH)2. [H = 1.0, 0 = 16.0, Ca = 40.0]",
A: "42",
B: "57",
C: "74",
D: "87",
answer: "C. 74",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. A reflex action....................",
A: "can be controlled.",
B: "depends on previous experience.",
C: "depends on memory.",
D: "is spontaneous.",
answer: "D. is spontaneous",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following statements is correct?",
A: "Light travels faster in water than in air.",
B: "Sound travels faster in air than in wood.",
C: "Sound waves are longitudinal waves.",
D: "Light waves are elastic waves.",
answer: "C. Sound waves are longitudinal waves",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. During a hot day, the receptors in human skin cause ......................",
A: "dilation of superficial blood vessels.",
B: "constriction of superficial blood vessels",
C: "lowering of hairs on the skin.",
D: "a decrease in metabolic rate.",
answer: "A. dilation of superficial blood vessels",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. A system of levers has a velocity ratio of 5. If an effort of 10 N overcomes a load of 40 N what would be the efficiency of the lever system?",
A: "25%",
B: "60%",
C: "80%",
D: "100%",
answer: "C. 80%",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. The phenotypic ratio of selfing the offspring of a cross between homozygous tall and homozygous short orange plants is .........................",
A: "1:1",
B: "3:1",
C: "1:2:1",
D: "1:1:2",
answer: "B. 3:1",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. A clinical thermometer is not sterilized in boiling water because......................",
A: "a vector may contaminate it",
B: "it has a narrow bore",
C: "water has lower boiling point.",
D: "it has a short range overtemperature",
answer: "D. it has a short range of temperature",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The eradication of malaria is proving almost impossible in the tropics because of the ................",
A: "wide area of breeding grounds for the vector.",
B: "ineffectiveness 0f insecticide in use against the vector",
C: "absence of natural enemies of the vector",
D: "presence of thick. cuticle that protects the parasite.",
answer: "A. wide",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. The point in an object where all the forces acting on its particles pass is the object's",
A: "centre of curvature.",
B: "centre of gravity.",
C: "centre of mass",
D: "midpoint.",
answer: "B. centre of gravity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Which of the following chemical formulae represents Lead (II) oxide?",
A: "Pb2O",
B: "PbO",
C: "PbO2",
D: "Pb2O4",
answer: "B. PbO",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question51",
question: "51. A block and tackle system has five fixed pulleys and four moving ones. What is the velocity ratio of the system?",
A: "1",
B: "4",
C: "5",
D: "9",
answer: "D. 9",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. The pituitary gland is referred to as the master gland because ........................",
A: "it secretes a lot of hormones.",
B: "it secretes growth hormones",
C: "it controls the other members of the endocrine system.",
D: "its hormones may cause giantism.",
answer: "C. it controls the other members of the endocrine system",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. A body moves with a velocity of 30.0 ms-1 • If the speed is increased to 40.0 ms-1 in 4.0ms-1, calculate the average acceleration of the body.",
A: "2.5 ms-2",
B: "4.4 ms-2",
C: "8.8 ms-2",
D: "17.5 ms-2",
answer: "A. 2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question54",
question: "54. Which of the following substances can cause temporary hardness of water?",
A: "Calcium hydrogen trioxocarbonate (IV)",
B: "Calcium trioxocarbonate (IV)",
C: "Potassium trioxocarbcnate (IV)",
D: "Sodium trioxocarbonate (IV)",
answer: "A. Calcium hydrogen trioxocarbonate (IV)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question55",
question: "55. Which of the following pests bores through grains?",
A: "Aphids",
B: "Army worms",
C: "Mealy-bugs",
D: "Weevils",
answer: "D. Weevils",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. If 4.52 x 105J of heat energy was used to vapourize 200.0 g of boiling water, calculate the specific heat of vaporization of water.",
A: "2.26 X 105 J kg-1",
B: "2.26 X 106 J kg-1",
C: "22.6 X 106 J kg-1",
D: "226 X 106 J kg-1",
answer: "B. 2",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question57",
question: "57. Which of the following people is not associated with a classification system?",
A: "Aristotle",
B: "Linnaeus",
C: "Mendel",
D: "Mendeleev",
answer: "C. Mendel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question58",
question: "58. Which of the following methods cannot be used to protect iron against rust?",
A: "Enamelling",
B: "Galvanizing",
C: "Painting",
D: "Riveting",
answer: "D. Riveting",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. One advantage steel has over iron in construction is that it is .....................",
A: "ductile.",
B: "malleable.",
C: "elastic.",
D: "shiny.",
answer: "B. malleable",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. The S.I unit of the moment of a force is .............................",
A: "kg/m.",
B: "kgm/s",
C: "N/m.",
D: "Nm",
answer: "D. Nm",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},



]